



 

   //Questions array

   let questions = [

    {

         number:1,

         question: " ___ refers to the body of poems composed by unknown persons song among members of the society and transferred from one generation to the other",

         answer : "oral poetry",

         options : [

                          "Oral poetry",

                          "Ancient poetry",

                          "Modern poetry",

                          "Written poetry"

                        ]

    

    },

    {

         number:2,

         question: "__ is traceable to the early greco-roman poetry",

         answer : "Lyric",

         options : [

                          "Lyric",

                          "Ode",

                          "Sonnet",

                          "Haiku"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:3,

         question: " ___ originated from Italy",

         answer : "Sonnet",

         options : [

                          "Haiku",

                          "Ode",

                          "Sonnet",

                          "Lyric"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:4,

         question: "Lyric poetry focuses on __",

         answer : "Expressing emotion",

         options : [

                          "Expressing emotion",

                          "Use of figurative device",

                          "Storytelling",

                          "Making of Melody"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:5,

         question: "___ deals with the thoughts and meditations of the poet addressed to an idea, object or a person.",

         answer : "Ode",

         options : [

                          "Epic",

                          "Elegy",

                          "Ballad",

                          "Ode"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:6,

         question: "___ is a poem of 14 lines",

         answer : "Sonnet",

         options : [

                          "Lyric",

                          "Sonnet",

                          "Ode",

                          "Lyric"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:7,

         question: "A poetic form that tends to mourn the death of an individual or number of people is",

         answer : "Elegy",

         options : [

                          "Ode",

                          "Elegy",

                          "Epic",

                          "Ballad"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:8,

         question: "A sonnet is written in ___",

         answer : "Iambic pentameter",

         options : [

                          "Iambic pentameter",

                          "Didactic picture",

                          "Octaves",

                          "Free verse"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:9,

         question: "Which is not a type of sonnet",

         answer : "Alexandrian sonnet",

         options : [

                          "Shakespearean sonnet",

                          "Petrarchan sonnet",

                          "Spenserian sonnet",

                          "Alexandrian sonnet"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:10,

         question: "The oldest form of sonnet is",

         answer : "Petrarchan sonnet",

         options : [

                          "Spenserian sonnet",

                          "Petrarchan sonnet",

                          "Alexandrian sonnet",

                          "Shakespearean sonnet"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:11,

         question: "A group of sonnets on a related theme is known as",

         answer : "Sonnet sequence",

         options : [

                          "Sonnet Couplet",

                          "Sonnet Octave",

                          "Sonnet sequence",

                          "Sonnet circle"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:12,

         question: "Elegy often uses __ figure of speech",

         answer : "Apostrophe",

         options : [

                          "Hyperbole",

                          "Metonymy",

                          "Oxymoron",

                          "Apostrophe"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:13,

         question: "__ poetry originated from Japan",

         answer : "Haiku",

         options : [

                          "Haiku",

                          "Ode",

                          "Sonnet",

                          "Lyric"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:14,

         question: "___ is a song like poem that tells a story",

         answer : "Ballad",

         options : [

                          "Elegy",

                          "Ballad",

                          "Ode",

                          "Epic"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:15,

         question: "The shortest type of poem is",

         answer : "Haiku",

         options : [

                          "Didactic",

                          "Haiku",

                          "Ode",

                          "Epic"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:16,

         question: "__ is a long narrative that they relate to the great deeds of a larger-than-life hero",

         answer : "Epic",

         options : [

                          "Didactic",

                          "Haiku",

                          "Ballad",

                          "Epic"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:17,

         question: "___ is an anonymous traditional story that usually explains a belief, custom or mysterious phenomenon",

         answer : "Myth",

         options : [

                          "Myth",

                          "Dirge",

                          "Saga",

                          "Didactic"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:18,

         question: "Epic is sometimes referred to as",

         answer : "Saga",

         options : [

                          "Myth",

                          "Saga",

                          "Dirge",

                          "Didactic"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:19,

         question: "___ is a song of lamentation chanted during or after the burial of a loved one",

         answer : "Dirge",

         options : [

                          "Myth",

                          "Didactic",

                          "Dirge",

                          "Saga"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:20,

         question: "The most important myths of the ancient world are that of ___",

         answer : "Greece",

         options : [

                          "Persia",

                          "Babylon",

                          "Egypt",

                          "Greece"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:21,

         question: "Which of these is not an example of a primary epic",

         answer : "Paradise Lost",

         options : [

                          "Iliad",

                          "Paradise Lost",

                          "Epic of Gilgamesh",

                          "Beowulf"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:22,

         question: "Which of these is not an example of a secondary epic",

         answer : "Homer’s Odyssey",

         options : [

                          "The fairy Queen",

                          "Homer’s Odyssey",

                          "Vigil’s Aeneid",

                          "Jerusalem delivered"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:23,

         question: "__ poetry has the primary purpose of imparting knowledge",

         answer : "Didactic",

         options : [

                          "Myth",

                          "Dirge",

                          "Didactic",

                          "Saga"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:24,

         question: "___ is simply a form of poetry based on unrhymed lines and lack of regular meter",

         answer : "Free verse",

         options : [

                          "Iambic verse",

                          "Free verse",

                          "Blank verse",

                          "Indented verse"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:25,

         question: "The most important metrical form used in English dramatic and epic poetry is",

         answer : "Blank verse",

         options : [

                          "Iambic verse",

                          "Indented verse",

                          "Free verse",

                          "Blank verse"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:26,

         question: "Praise poetry is also known as",

         answer : "Panegyric",

         options : [

                          "Eulogy",

                          "Epic",

                          "Panegyric",

                          "Ballad"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:27,

         question: "Two consecutive lines of poetry that rhyme is known as",

         answer : "Couplet",

         options : [

                          "Couplet",

                          "Tercet",

                          "Pentameter",

                          "Doublet"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:28,

         question: "The most common verse unit in English poetry is",

         answer : "Quatrain",

         options : [

                          "Couplet",

                          "Terza Rima",

                          "Octave",

                          "Quatrain"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:29,

         question: "__ is an interlocking 3 line stanza form",

         answer : "Terza Rima",

         options : [

                          "Triad",

                          "Terza Rima",

                          "Triplet",

                          "Tercet"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:30,

         question: "___ refers to an eighth-line stanza",

         answer : "Octave",

         options : [

                          "Octave",

                          "Quatrain",

                          "Pentameter",

                          "Couplet"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:31,

         question: "___ is the central idea or meaning of a story",

         answer : "Theme",

         options : [

                          "Plot",

                          "Subject matter",

                          "Topic sentence",

                          "Theme"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:32,

         question: "___ is the underlying structure of a story",

         answer : "Plot",

         options : [

                          "Topic sentence",

                          "Plot",

                          "Theme",

                          "Subject matter"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:33,

         question: "___ is the process or technique by which the writer reveals the personality of a character",

         answer : "Characterization",

         options : [

                          "Prompting",

                          "Denouement",

                          "Characterization",

                          "Casting"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:34,

         question: "The most exciting part of a plot is",

         answer : "Climax",

         options : [

                          "Climax",

                          "Denouement",

                          "Rising action",

                          "Falling action"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:35,

         question: "All the problems or mysteries of the plot unraveled in __",

         answer : "Denouement",

         options : [

                          "Falling action",

                          "Climax",

                          "Denouement",

                          "Rising action"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:36,

         question: "God is a character in which of these poems",

         answer : "The pulley",

         options : [

                          "Jerusalem delivered",

                          "The pulley",

                          "Odyssey",

                          "Beowulf"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:37,

         question: "Which of these is not a sub division of long poems",

         answer : "Lines",

         options : [

                          "Lines",

                          "Book",

                          "Stanza",

                          "Canto"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:38,

         question: "___ is a subdivision in a long poem corresponding to a chapter in a book",

         answer : "Canto",

         options : [

                          "Canto",

                          "Stanza",

                          "Lines",

                          "Book"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:39,

         question: "Book is typical of__ poems",

         answer : "Epic",

         options : [

                          "Eulogy",

                          "Epic",

                          "Ballad",

                          "Panegyric"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:40,

         question: "The shortest subdivision of long poems is",

         answer : "Stanzas",

         options : [

                          "Book",

                          "Stanzas",

                          "Lines",

                          "Part"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:41,

         question: "Canto is equivalent to __ subdivision of long poems",

         answer : "Part",

         options : [

                          "Stanzas",

                          "Lines",

                          "Book",

                          "Part"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:42,

         question: "The most common type of rhyme is",

         answer : "Syllabic rhyme",

         options : [

                          "Approximate rhyme",

                          "Perfect rhyme",

                          "Syllabic rhyme",

                          "End of tail rhyme"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:43,

         question: "When words sound similar but do not rhyme exactly they are called",

         answer : "Approximate rhymes",

         options : [

                          "Syllabic rhymes",

                          "Approximate rhymes",

                          "Perfect rhymes",

                          "End of tail rhymes"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:44,

         question: "___ is a reiterating of a word or phrase within a poem",

         answer : "Repetition",

         options : [

                          "Rhythm",

                          "Alliteration",

                          "Refrain",

                          "Repetition"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:45,

         question: "___ is the alternation of stressed and unstressed syllables in language",

         answer : "Rhythm",

         options : [

                          "Rhythm",

                          "Rhyme",

                          "Assonance",

                          "Repetition"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:46,

         question: "___ is the repetition of one or more phrases or lines at intervals in a poem",

         answer : "Refrain",

         options : [

                          "Alliteration",

                          "Refrain",

                          "Rhythm",

                          "Repetition"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:47,

         question: "___ is repetition of similar sounds",

         answer : "Rhyme",

         options : [

                          "Alliteration",

                          "Rhyme",

                          "Repetition",

                          "Refrain"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:48,

         question: "One of these is not a kind of irony",

         answer : "Literary irony",

         options : [

                          "Literary irony",

                          "Verbal irony",

                          "Dramatic irony",

                          "Situational irony"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:49,

         question: "When an event occurs that directly contradicts expectations__ is said to have happened",

         answer : "Situational irony",

         options : [

                          "Situational irony",

                          "Literary irony",

                          "Dramatic irony",

                          "Verbal irony"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:50,

         question: "___ occurs when the audience or reader knows something important that a character in a play does not know",

         answer : "Dramatic irony",

         options : [

                          "Verbal irony",

                          "Literary irony",

                          "Situational irony",

                          "Dramatic irony"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:51,

         question: "When words are used to suggest the opposite of their usual meaning, __ occurs",

         answer : "Verbal irony",

         options : [

                          "Literary irony",

                          "Verbal irony",

                          "Dramatic irony",

                          "Situational irony"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:52,

         question: "__ is the use of language to hurt the hearer’s feelings",

         answer : "Sacarsm",

         options : [

                          "Apostrophe",

                          "Satire",

                          "Euphemism",

                          "Sacarsm"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:53,

         question: "The president kicked the bucket yesterday. This sentence is an example of",

         answer : "Euphemism",

         options : [

                          "Allusion",

                          "Euphemism",

                          "Oxymoron",

                          "Synecdoche"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:54,

         question: "___ is a reference to a statement, person, place, event or thing that is known from literature",

         answer : "Allusion",

         options : [

                          "Allusion",

                          "Apostrophe",

                          "Satire",

                          "Euphemism"  

                          ]

    

    }

     ];   